Value Village closeout sale

Day 00726: Thursday, 2017 March 02

General news

Before work, I headed to the second-hand store next door to my workplace to return the dysfunctional shredder. The cashier told me to go pick out an item of equal value to basically trade for, so I tried to do that. I found two baking dishes that combined would be of greater value, and planned to pay the difference. At that point, I realized that I don't have oven mitts. What good are baking dishes without oven mitts? The store didn't have any oven mitts for me to buy too though, so I'd have to wait to use my new baking dishes. I also looked into getting a water-resistant coat, but the coats there were too expensive for me.

I took my selections to the front counter, but it turned out that one of the baking dishes was part of a set. To buy it, I'd need to locate the other piece. I didn't have time for that, I was already almost late to work. I asked if there was any way that I could save the credit for another day. I was almost certain that I couldn't and I'd need to keep the shredder and return it another day. However, they put the money on a gift card for me. Why couldn't they have done that in the first place instead of asking me to go get an item of equal value!? Had they done that, I wouldn't have wasted time trying to find a second baking dish I liked; I'd have just saved part of the credit. I didn't have time to spend part of the credit on the baking dish I wanted more and that didn't have a second piece either; there wasn't time, and they initially loaded the full credit on the card instead of applying part of it to the baking dish.

At work, one of the customers asked me about my move, so I said that it went well, but I'm still missing a few key items. They asked what I was missing, so I mentioned that I don't have a bed frame, oven mitts, and some other items that I don't recall. They said that the Dollar Tree has oven mitts. Nice! It'll take me some time to get over there, but they'll be less expensive than second-hand oven mitts for sure.

It seems that Value Village, the second-hand store closer to my home, is going out of business. Sad. They're having a closeout sale on the eleventh, twelfth, and thirteenth though, and everything will be fifty percent off, so I'll go check that out. I'll probably try to make in in on the eleventh, when they still have the largest selection, but I'll also probably be going again on the twelfth as well. A friend from work invited me to go along with themself and another friend from work. It's a great excuse to hang out for a bit, so I don't want to miss that, but I also want to get a chance to check out the larger selection.

Once I got home, I spent the rest of the night washing laundry and working on coursework.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

My PHIL 1404 reading assignment for the week is as follows:

1. Introduction
2. What is bullying at work?
4. Causes of bullying at work
5. Consequences of bullying at work
Racial Discrimination
Gender Discrimination and Occupational Segregation
Discrimination: Inferiority versus Aptness
The Diversity of Discrimination and Victimization
The Prevention and Rectification of Discrimination: Affirmative Action
Case Studies
Is There Anything Special about Sex?
Bad Sex: Harassment
Drugged
The Organization Wants You to Use Drugs?
Case Studies

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A confusing tip

Day 00727: Friday, 2017 March 03

General news

I ... feel so strange not using names to refer to my coworkers in my journal. Lately, I've been discussing my coworkers a lot, but for their privacy, I've not been mentioning them by name. The privacy shall continue though.

The coworker that offered to check over my essays wrote back today about last week's essay. Apparently, they couldn't figure out how to turn on email notifications, so they missed my email and didn't see it until the essay was past due. Hmm. I wonder it would be easier for them if I used the SMS gateways.

I wrote to my mother this morning. I've been dreading doing that, but I knew I needed to initiate communication at some point to keep us from falling into a permanent radio silence. Ideally, I'd wait long enough for my mother to cool down, but not too long as to make my mother think I'm avoiding them. I can't see my mother though, I don't know if they've cooled down yet or not. Today though, I had a perfect and time-sensitive excuse: the Value Village sale. I've now been invited over to keep the cat company for the weekend, and Vanessa and our mother will be away. I don't really want to go over there, but I'll have to anyway at some point to take care of the restroom and finish the dishes. It might as well be this weekend, as long as I can keep up with coursework as well.

I briefly considered making my mother's house my base of operations for the weekend. That'd get me closer to the Dollar Tree to pick up oven mitts. That'd be a *very* bad idea though. Even if I bring laundry such as work uniforms, I'm not effective there because of the toxic atmosphere. Furthermore, there's no food! I'm not going to perform well in my studies without decent nutrition. Even the thought of going over there made me unproductive even here at home. Hopefully though, I'll finish up my reading assignment and learning journal assignment tomorrow.

I was gypped for hours this coming work week, it seems. Also, my days off have shifted and my one morning shift has been switched to an evening shift. In general, I'd rather work all morning shifts or all night shifts, but I had plans for this Sunday. Oh well, I'll just have to shift stuff a bit. The work week after this coming work week though ... If I don't have that evening free, I won't be able to go to the Value Village sale with my friends from work. Oh well, there's nothing I can do if that happens. I mean, I could get someone to cover my shift or something, but I can't afford to lose the hours.

Lately, I've been taking a different approach to dealing with customers that can't read signs and refuse to listen to directions. Previously, if they skipped the menu board and waited by the window, which our signs tell them not to do, I'd politely ask them to use the menu board next time, then I'd take their order at the window. Now, I've been ignoring them until they either read the sign on the window telling them to place orders at the menu board or they figure out by other means that they need to go back to the menu board. Is it less efficient? Very much so. However, customers no longer complain. It takes them longer to get their food, but they understand that they're the ones doing it wrong and they don't blame me for their own failure to figure out how to use a restaurant drive-through. When I ask customers at the menu board to wait there for a bit and they refuse, I no longer confront them about it. It's not worth it. They're being incredibly rude by refusing to follow basic drive-through etiquette. They're slowing down the processing of their own order by refusing to follow directions so I have to run back and forth between the window and where I'm working. However, they've made it clear that they *want* to be a pain in the neck, so I haven't been giving them a chance to be an even bigger pain; especially because my boss, the one who gave me the instructions to get customers to order/wait at the menu board won't even back me up.

That one moronic customer that threatened to get me fired for doing my job came through tonight. As I said though, I'm no longer confronting customers and trying to get them to follow basic drive-through etiquette or basic drive-through protocol, so they didn't have anything to complain about. Apparently, they didn't recognize my voice through the menu board; I don't blame them, I didn't recognize them either. They had order money and tip money pulled out, but when they saw may face, I saw them recognize me; they had a look of distaste once they knew who I was. They removed the tip money and just paid for their food. I didn't mind, as long as they weren't going to try something nasty, but strangely, they gave me the tip a bit later. They seemed to debate a bit before doing so, but why would they choose to give it to me? Why would they be debating at all instead of just keeping it? They don't like me; they want me gone. Why would they be giving me extra money? I certainly won't complain about getting an extra dollar for the day, but I'm very confused as to what they were thinking.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I don't recall much of my dream last night, but what I remember is strange. I was in a retail store. I saw a camera flash, and turned around. There was a giant mobile device screen at one point overlayed on reality; it showed a camera application and represented the fact that someone was taking a photograph from that direction, even though the giant device was flipped the wrong direction for that. At that point, I started trying to be covert for some reason, and started moving some strange contraption. I don't even recall what it looked like, but it had some of those curly telephone cords on it. Unfortunately, one of my real-life shift leaders came over and started talking to me while I was trying to be sneaky, so I had to get out of there quickly. I'm not sure if I recognized them as a shift leader in the dream, but I recognized them as someone I knew by name, face, and voice. I made a bad turn, not keeping far away enough from a shelf, and the curly telephone wires got snagged on the shelf. I'm not sure why, but there wasn't time. I couldn't stop to properly detangle the device from the shelf, so I had to leave it behind. I was a bit frustrated with my shift leader for that. It wasn't my shift leader that I was trying to evade, but I now tried to escape my shift leader as well simply because they wanted to talk. I couldn't be covert with someone making noise and drawing attention to my location. As I made my way through the store, I noticed that I was wearing the drive-through headset, though I'm not sure why. Fairly soon though, I stumbled upon a reflective surface; I think it was a hard-cover book, but I don't recall. My headset's lights were green; I could see the one on the microphone sticking out in front of me. However, the light reflecting off the reflective surface was red.

At that point, I knew I was dreaming. My shift leader caught up with me, but it no longer mattered. Nothing was real. I told my shift leader that I was only dreaming, but they didn't know what I meant. I was lucid, so I tried to figure out something I could do with the dream, but I was at a loss for ideas. Soon after, I just decided to wake up because I couldn't think of anything else to do and was kind of bored.

University life

I'm not going to repeat myself here, as I've already gone over the details in my learning journal. This week's assignment is an assessment of the reading material (listed yesterday) in our learning journals. One section of the reading in particular caught my attention: a section on the effects on the victims of bullying at work. I show so many symptoms, it's not even funny. Except ... I've never felt bullied at work. Sure, the head manager calls me a hippie and says that my music isn't very manly, but I don't personally take either as an insult. I actually care about the planet, unlike most people, and if that makes me a hippie, so be it. The boss even asked me on one occasion if I mind being called a hippie; the implication being that they'd stop if I actually cared. As for listening to manly music, I don't consider myself masculine, so I don't need to pretend to be. I'm agendered; I can listen to whatever I want and dress however I want. However, I was bullied at home until recently. For decades, my mother's been doing nothing but tearing apart my ego. It shows too, apparently. It seems that my ... cynical view of the world very much could be a symptom of abuse and not simply be me being able to see what most people choose to ignore. That said, perhaps it's there for any who choose to see, but the unabused have the luxury of being capable of ignoring it.

Tomorrow, I choose my courses for the coming term. I went over my course requirement/prerequisite tree to start thinking about what courses to take. CS 1102: Programming 1 is a given. I need that course to unlock CS 1103: Programming 2, which itself will unlock several branches of my tree, so I need to get that out of the way as soon as possible; if CS 1102 weren't offered in a given term, and I waited until that term to take it, I'd be stuck in my progress for at least a term. Even more likely, if I wait to take this, I won't have a second course to take alongside it. I started looking at my requirements that can be filled by multiple courses as well. After trying to decide which requirements to choose, I remembered that I'd already chosen. There's room to change my mind, but there's no need to stress over this now, especially for courses I don't plan to take this term anyway. As one of my courses next term won't be proctored, I don't want the other to be either. I'd rather condense my proctored courses into fewer terms, so I have less proctored terms to worry about. HIST 1421: Greek and Roman Civilization is my only other available, non-optional, unproctored course, so I'll probably try to take that one.

I finally mailed my tuition payment to University of [REDACTED]. It costs an extra forty-nine cents to do this by mail instead of through an electronic payment, but it's well worth it for a number of reasons. First, I don't have to deal with PayPal's garbage. Second, the university doesn't have to pay PayPal's fee; that is to say, the university gets to keep more of the money. Third, PayPal *doesn't* get a cut. They're a horrid company and don't deserve any of it. They do nothing but hassle me and make everything they touch difficult.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Registering for next term's courses

Day 00729: Sunday, 2017 March 05

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A bicycle
A bicycle helmet
A trash bin
A recycling bin
A scrubbers
Towels

Hand towels
Bath towels

Some sort of container to keep socks and underwear in
A shower curtain
A shower curtain rod
A broom
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

The post office (change of address forms)
Relevant online accounts
My boss

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)

General news

I completed my reading assignment and learning journal entry before going to bed last night, just after midnight. I'd hoped to have it completed before then so I could go to bed sooner, but honestly, I didn't use my time as efficiently as I should have yesterday morning. Once I woke up, I packed my work uniform and headed to my mother's house to clean the bathroom, wash the dishes, and (I guess) provide company to my mother's cat for a bit. On the way to my mother's place, it snowed. Joy. I hate snow; it's cold and wet.

When I got to my mother's house, my mother's cat was excited. It might have been lonely or it might have missed me, but I suspect the former. Perhaps I'm just projecting though; I have no strong ties to the cat. Honestly though, back when I lived there, the cat preferred my company over my mother's; my mother's too controlling, even towards the cat.

The dishes were lower than they would have been had I still been living there. There was about a week and a half worth of cooking dishes, but almost no eating dishes due to my mother having switched to paper plates in my absence. I cleaned all of the dishes save for one plastic straw, which would need to be soaked in bleach. I didn't want to stay that long. I scrubbed the bathroom sink, counter, and toilet, all by hand. I accidentally dripped cleanser in the cat's water bowl, so I washed that out as well and gave it fresh water. I should have scrubbed the floor and the shower, but that will have to wait until another trip. Being in that house ... It makes me sluggish and very easily distracted. I had to get out of there.

Once I got home, I started working on my CS 1101 coursework, but after setting up the page for the assignment and having just updated the navigation menus and coursework index to account for my new course registrations, I finally started a side project I've been meaning to work on. Every time I need to add a course or assignment, I have to edit two different files. One is the coursework index and the other, among other things, controls the navigation menus. I have to search through both files and make sure to make the insertions in the right places. For now, it's not too bad, but making two edits instead of one wastes time. As my coursework list grows, it'll also take longer to find the right place to add the new entries. I'm done with that now. I now have code set up so I can make a single insertion, and the scripts will take care of the rest for me. It took a couple hours to set up; programming always takes longer than I think it will. I completed it just before I had to head in to work though.

I haven't updated my to-do list to account for recent events lately, so after work, I took care of that.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

I forgot to register for courses yesterday, so I registered for them today. CS 1102 seems to be a course on Java. Ew, Java. I will need to know Java to develop mobile applications though, so this refresher course will be a good thing, even if unpleasant. In addition to CS 1102, I also registered for HIST 1421 as planned. I almost couldn't find HIST 1421 in the list of available courses; the list seemed jumbled and disorganized. It turned out the courses were alphabetized by course name though, not course code. I'll have to keep that in mind for next registration period so I can more quickly locate the courses I need. I've updated my course tree to reflect the new registrations, but there hasn't been any update to the courses I plan to take:

CS 1101: Programming Fundamentals

CS 1102: Programming 1

CS 1103: Programming 2

CS 1104: Computer Systems

CS 2204: Communications and Networking

CS 4404: Advanced Networking and Data Security*

CS 2205: Web Programming 1 (proctored course)

CS 3305: Web Programming 2 (proctored course)*
CS 4405: Mobile Applications*

CS 2301: Operating Systems 1 (proctored course)

CS 3307: Operating Systems 2*

CS 2401: Software Engineering 1

CS 4403: Software Engineering 2*

CS 3303: Data Structures*

CS 3304: Analysis of Algorithms*

CS 4406: Computer Graphics (proctored course)*
CS 4407: Data Mining and Machine Learning (proctored course)*

CS 4408: Artificial Intelligence (proctored course)*

CS 3308: Information Retrieval (proctored course)*

CS 4402: Comparative Programming Languages*

CS 2203: Databases 1

CS 3306: Databases 2 (proctored course)*

ENGL 1102: English Composition 2 (proctored course)
HIST 1421: Greek and Roman Civilization
MATH 1201: College Algebra (proctored course)

MATH 1211: Calculus*

MATH 1280: Introduction to Statistics (proctored course)
MATH 1302: Discrete Mathematics*
PHIL 1404: Ethics and Social Responsibility
UNIV 1001: Online Education Strategies

Any one of these:

BIOL 1121: Biology 1 for Health Studies Majors
BIOL 1301: Introduction to Biology
ENVS 1301: Introduction to Environmental Science

Any one (two*) of these:

ECON 1580: Introduction to Economics
POLS 1503: Globalization
PSYC 1111: Introduction to Human Psychology
PSYC 1205: Emotional Intelligence
PSYC 1504: Introduction to Psychology
SOC 1502: Introduction to Sociology

Any one (two*) of these:

AHIST 1401: Art History
ENGL 1405: World Literature
PHIL 1402: Introduction to Philosophy

Any two (five*) electives

BUS 1101: Principles of Business Management

BUS 1102: Basic Accounting (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)

BUS 2203: Principles of Finance 1 (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)

BUS 1103: Microeconomics (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)
BUS 1104: Macroeconomics (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)
BUS 2201: Principles of Marketing (proctored course) (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)

BUS 2207: Multinational Management

BUS 4403: Business Policies & Strategies (proctored course) (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)***

BUS 4402: Organization Behavior (proctored course) (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)
BUS 3306: Business and Society

BUS 4403: Business Policies & Strategies (proctored course) (must score 2.67/4.0 or higher)***

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I got the stove working!

Day 00731: Tuesday, 2017 March 07

Unsponsored advertisements

Marc With a C just released a new single called Song For The Sad Girls. They released it on four different websites, but not their usual Bandcamp page. Unfortunately, the song has no license if gotten from three of them, while on the fourth (linked to above), there doesn't seem to be a way to download it. It's under the CC BY 3.0 license, but you can't actually download it; you can only listen using the Web interface. I tried looking up download instructions, which said I needed an account to download anything, but that not all songs are available for download. Someone wouldn't place a song under a free license though and disallow downloading though, would they? So I set up an account. On the first registration page, I was asked for my age. Why does that even matter? Apparently, the age must be numeric, cannot have more than three digits, and must be over thirteen. I chose "999". On the next page, I was asked for my gender. Why do they even care!? After seeing the minimum of thirteen part on the age thing, I thought that maybe they were just trying to keep young people out. Y'know, because a ten-year-old can't read the error message saying that you must be at least thirteen, then change the number to thirteen and submit again. But there's no reason for them to ask for a gender. However, they list four options for your gender: "male" (which is a sex, not a gender), "female" (which is also a sex and not a gender), "prefer not to say", and "custom". After selecting "custom", you can enter whatever you want! If they're going to ask you for your gender, that's exactly what they should do: let you actually specify something instead of demanding you choose a binary option or claim to prefer not to say. Some of us don't fall into one of the binary categories, but that doesn't mean we're not wanting to say what we are. It took forever for the confirmation email to get through, which was required for completing account setup. At least they actually confirm email addresses though. It sucks when I get emails from other people's accounts because some idiot website didn't make sure that the email address provided actually belonged to the account holder. Once everything was set up, I went back to the song page to find ... no download link. I still couldn't download the song. What the heck!? I ended up finding a third-party "downloader" website, and using that. It didn't actually download the song to send me though, I think it just located the URI of the song on SoundCloud's other-domain server, then gave me the link. With that, I could download it directly from SoundCloud. SoundCloud's complicated page code just made it too difficult for me to find that link myself (though I did try).

General news

I fixed the stove today. I really didn't want to get blamed for the fact it was broken, so I did my best to figure out why it wasn't working. I removed the busted burner and examined it, finding a break in the metal. That must be the issue, right? With that piece broken, the circuit was incomplete. Except ... after trying to bend the metal back into place for a while to bride the gap, I noticed that it didn't make sense for electricity to flow through that spot. If it did, it'd short circuit the burner and no power would pass through the heating element. That break was mostly cosmetic. Perhaps it held the power plugs in the right position though. Putting the burner back in, I found that it quickly heated up this time. My best guess is that the property managers took the burner off to clean under it after the last tenant moved out, then didn't make sure it was replaced properly. They either broke the metal when they took it out or some previous tenant broke it at some point. Without the metal intact, making sure the burner is connected properly takes a little more effort. In any case, I now have a working main burner!

SafeLink messaged me today. They've cut of my service, even though it's not quite April yet. When I have time, I should apply for service with another provider, but I don't have time today or tomorrow.

Speaking of not having time tomorrow, I gave up my only day off this school week (tomorrow). I had plans to catch up on the ungraded exercises I've been unable to complete the past two weeks, but I might have to settle for simply getting my graded work and exercises from this week done.

My electric bill came today. It claims that I owe them four dollars from last month, and that that payment's overdue! I still have my receipt from last month though, so I'll have to show them that I payed my bill in full last time.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

My program advisor wrote to me today, suggesting I pay my tuition bill and saying it'd only take a minute. A minute? More like two hours! I've already sent my payment though, all I can do is wait for it to make its way through the mail. I wrote back, saying about as much:

Dear [REDACTED],

Ha ha, it takes a lot longer than a minute! I have to run to the credit union to get a cashier's cheque, which is about half an hour there and the same back, then run to the post office to mail it, which is another half hour there and another back. It takes about two hours to pay, not a minute. PayPal locked up my credit card. They refuse to allow me to pay the university. Until University of [REDACTED] offers a way to pay by credit card that *isn't* through PayPal, it'll take about two hours to pay every term.

On a more serious note though, I've already sent the cashier's cheque. I'm not sure how quickly it'll reach the school; all we can do is wait.

Thank you,
~ [REDACTED]

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Limiting my use of characters in URIs

Day 00734: Friday, 2017 March 10

General news

https:- and http:-scheme URI syntax isn't really defined. At all. RFC 3986 defines general URI syntax, which includes potential delimiters for specific schemes to use, and RFC 7230 sets aside the schemes themselves for use to identify Web files. However, without scheme-specific syntax defined, it's hard to say whether it's fine to use sometimes-delimiters in Web addresses. It's not technically *disallowed* though, so at first, I used an apostrophe in the URI of my essay submission for the week. I later realized that was a bad idea and changed it though. The problem is the ambiguity. On one side of the argument, you could say that the ambiguity prevents us from knowing whether these characters need to be encoded in https:-scheme URIs. Perhaps they're *required* to be encoded, but perhaps they're *required* to be unencoded. We just don't know, so it's safest to avoid those characters altogether. I take the other side though. I think both options are allowed. And that's where *my* reason not to use them comes in. They're both allowed, but unless your Web server is set up to handle all potential delimiters as having a meaning outside of HTTP itself, the URI with the encoded character and the URI with the unencoded character will point to the same file. Unless you have a special setup, keeping one and only one URI pointing to the page requires that you not use these ambiguously-allowed characters. Sure, having use of a slightly-larger character set is nice, but not when it causes ambiguity issues, such as having a page under two URIs. (Which URI is the correct one?)

I was supposed to stop at the credit union before work, but due to my variable work schedule, I thought that I was supposed to head into work an hour after I was really supposed to leave. I caught the mistake just as I was headed out, and had to head strait to work instead of hitting up the credit union first. I'll just have to hope the cash I have on hand is enough for tomorrow, when I go to the Value Village sale.

I had a customer come through the drive-through with the smallest order I've seen so far: a single cup of marinara sauce, which costs fifty cents. I think that's our cheapest item, so I'm not going to see any smaller orders later, either. Later, a customer placed an order at the menu board, and when I asked them to pay at the window, they instead drove off. I had no choice but to cancel their order. Later, they came by to pick it up, but obviously, we didn't have it. They ended up having to wait again just because they didn't listen the first time and pay for their order. If you don't pay for your order, we can't make it for you.

Toward the end of the night, the power went out on us. Right as I got my mobile's flashlight turned on though, the power came back. A later customer reported seeing emergency vehicles including ambulances, so it's possible someone hit a power pole or something and knocked out our electricity for a few seconds.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

I've written up a first draft of my essay for the week, though I haven't completed the reading assignment yet. I might add more details if I come across something useful in the textbook later.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Sock and underwear drawers

Day 00735: Saturday, 2017 March 11

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A bicycle
A bicycle helmet
A scrubbers
Towels

Hand towels

Some sort of container to keep socks and underwear in
A broom
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

The post office (change of address forms)
Relevant online accounts
My boss

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)

General news

I had plenty of cash for the Value Village sale after all, partly because they're so cleaned out by now. They had absolutely nothing that I was actually looking for. I did pick up three pairs of black pants for work though, sort of as a last-minute decision. I rip my pants occasionally, for example, at work last night, so it's nice to have spare pairs on hand.

On the way home, I stopped at a yard sale I happened to see, and bought a set of those white, plastic drawers, so I now have a place to store my socks and underwear, or at least many of them. I also picked up three nice bath towels there.

I forgot to bring my second-hand store in-store credit card with me as I'd planned to, so I wasn't able to pick up the baking dish I wanted. Perhaps tomorrow.

Lately, I've been working on deciding tertiary elements to use in my Floraverse-based stories. According to Floraverse cannon, tertiary elements exist, though what exactly those elements *are* isn't defined in cannon. At work today, while washing dishes between customers, I tried to decide on what Acid and Clay would make when mixed. I've been working in alphabetical order, and that's where I'm stuck. I've come up with several out of order, but I try to focus most of my thoughts on the elements on one specific element combination at a time so I don't have to remember all the undefined combinations at once. For inspiration, I tried breaking Acid and Clay into their primary elements and rearranging them a bit. Acid is Fire * Water and Clay is Earth * Water, so the only other way to arrange these elements is (Water * Water) * (Earth * Fire), which is to say, Lava * Ice. That's another combination I stared at for a while on several occasions though and came up with nothing for. Combining Earth, Fire, Water, and Water isn't an easy task; I'm skipping it for now.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I love it here!

Day 00738: Tuesday, 2017 March 14

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A bicycle
A bicycle helmet
Scrubbers
Towels

Hand towels

A broom
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

The post office (change of address forms)
Relevant online accounts
My boss

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)

General news

This morning as I was working on coursework, I heard the sounds of a lawn mower outside and I realized something awesome. Here in an apartment, I don't have to deal with yard maintenance! I like a lawn full of several short, non-grass plants such as clovers, as long as they're not ugly plants that spread wide leaves to kill everything, like dandelions. Tall grass isn't all that appealing though. I don't have time or desire to engage in lawn care, so it's very nice to have someone else dealing with it for me.

I used to think I wanted a roommate. It'd make rent a bit cheaper, and the company wouldn't be that bad. After living here a while though, I've changed my mind. At least for the time being, living alone is worth the cost. I may try out having a roommate at some point, but for now, I like my current situation.

I can't use my mobile to its full potential without a home server. It's been months since I've had one, and I'm starting to forget many of the benefits, but CalDAV and CardDAV were pretty big. Without them, I kind of wonder if having mobile service is even worth it. However, I need the mobile service for its very slow Internet connection. My electric bill isn't as high as I feared though. My mother always made it out like the bill was super high, and maybe with six people living in the house, it was. On my own though ... with my low electric bill, maybe I can spend some money on cable Internet service. I'd discontinue my mobile service, as I don't need both, my maybe I could have a high-speed connection again and a home server! With a home connection, I'd set up at least two things. First, a Tor node, preferably an exit node. Second, an open Wi-Fi router. If I have an exit node, I might just set up the router normally; otherwise, I'll need to find a way to pipe the connection through Tor so any guests aren't coming from my IP address, but a Tor IP address.

I picked up some second-hand dish towels before work today. Slowly but surely, I'm gathering the basics I need here at home. What I need most at the moment though is a bike. Once I have that, everything else will be easier to get for a couple reasons. Not only will long-distance trips take less time, I'll save time even on my daily commute. I'll have more free time!

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed that my mother came to stay over at my place and did nothing but complain, saying the way I'd set up my apartment was dysfunctional. They also covered my counter with vases so I couldn't use my counter top and laid claim to one of my blankets, which they planned to take home with them when they went. Vivian, Cyrus, and Vanessa stayed over too, and I was heavily reminded of how our mother complains about Vivian and Cyrus' place as well.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I have a bicycle!

Day 00740: Thursday, 2017 March 16

General news

Today was going to be solely about getting a head start on my coursework for the week, but I needed a break, so I went looking for a pawn shop one of my coworkers had told me about. Supposedly, it was on "twenty something" Main Street, was going out of business, and was selling bikes for half off. I found the place, and the bikes were indeed half off, but they were still kind of pricey. A dog in the store startled me by jumping on me unexpectedly, but at least it wasn't vicious. It seemed only to want attention. Still, people shouldn't let their dogs jump on strangers. On the way, I found another pawn shop with bikes that were even more costly. I decided to try at Goodwill too, as it was just a bit further. There, I found a pretty decent-looking bike, still more expensive than I wanted it to be, but in better shape than the bikes at the pawn shops and at a lower price. I bought the bike along with a helmet, but as I prepared to ride home, the helmet strap broke. They took it back, but only gave me store credit for it. It might be a while before I return, but at least they said the credit won't expire.

This bike has shocks, which is really strange for me. I've never had a bike with shocks; the lack of resistance makes it feel like I'm on a bike with flat tires. I'll get used to it though, and riding off curbs at the end of blocks without ramps should be less unpleasant than before. I'm hoping the bike doesn't have any problems though. Unlike the helmet, it was sold as-is.

I went out and bought a bike lock tonight, and I'll likely pick up a helmet before work tomorrow.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Julian days

Day 00741: Friday, 2017 March 17

General news

I discovered today that my new bike came with a combination lock already attached to it. If I lock the bike up with a second lock, the bike'll look stolen. Great. I'd have to try every combination until I could get the lock off. Thankfully, I found the combo after 561 tries; less than half the 1296 possibilities.

I headed to work early today, hoping to drop off my backpack and run errands, but instead, I was asked to clock in early. I put off clocking in long enough to buy a helmet at Saint Vincent's next door, but I did clock in way early and wasn't able to return the bike lock I bought yesterday. Hopefully I'll have time tomorrow, but I have another errand tomorrow as well. I might not get to the bike lock right away.

That customer that wants me fired showed up again. As usual, I pretended I didn't recognize them and served them as politely as always. They seem to be grumpier every time I see them though. I think they're *wanting* a reason to complain, and since I'm not giving them one, there's nothing they can hold against me.

One of my shift leaders offered to give me piano lessons. I'd *really* love to take them up on that! However, between work and school, I'm not sure I have the time to commit. If I could get a four-year rain check, I'd almost certainly take them up on it, but I probably won't even be working there that long. I had to turn them down.

That same shift leader and I were discussing birthdays and other anniversaries. Anniversaries are not the same day as the initial event, so celebrating an anniversary isn't the same as celebrating the day of the initial event. Anyone that disputes this is dead wrong. However, my shift leader has the view that celebrating birthdays is a celebration of life. This is a very typical view of birthdays, and is arguably valid as long as you don't claim to be celebrating the actual day of birth (which would be the *birth date*, and not the *birthday*). A yearly celebration of life planned to coincide with the anniversary of your separation from your mother is well within the realm of sanity. However, because each successive birthday is one year further from the birth, each birthday is necessarily one year closer to death. For this reason, I find the celebration of birthdays to be incredibly morbid. Each time, you're pointing out that another year is gone and the person is closer to their own expiration date than before.

During this conversation, my shift leader brought up Julian days. I'm still not convinced that Julian days have anything to do with the matter of birthdays and other anniversaries, but I'd never heard of Julian days before. They're an interesting concept. Every day is numbered. Months and years aren't mentioned, so a single integer can represent the day. The concept's very similar to Unix timestamps, but for days instead of seconds. I've been using day numbers since the beginning of this journal, though my day zero is at the start of the journal. I didn't know there were any existing day number standards to choose from. When I have time, I might switch my day numbers over to this system. I don't calculate my day numbers by hand. Every instance of a day number on this entire website is inserted by calling a class instance as a function. All I'd have to do is change the __invoke() method of the class, change the object instantiation like to use a different class, or swap the instantiation out for a string variable corresponding with a function name. After doing that and building the new day-number-calculation code, every instance of a day number would change without any further effort.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

What's up with these carriers and charging a fee to pay your bill!?

Day 00742: Saturday, 2017 March 18

General news

I'd planned to head into the T-Mobile store sooner, but there simply hasn't been time. My autopay point is too close though, so I cut off my plan early this morning. It rained as I headed to the T-Mobile store to get the new plan activated. However, it seems the representative I spoke with before didn't know what they were talking about. They said a prepaid plan without an E911 fee was available. No such plan actually exists though. A postpaid plan is available, but it requires a credit check and autopay. If autopay isn't enabled, a five-dollar fee is added, and if you pay in person, autopay is automatically disabled. I'm tired of these autopay games. I asked the representative about reactivating my SIM card on my current plan, and it seems they can't do that in-store. If I can't get this mess sorted out, I might have to buy a new SIM card to get my plan back. Activating a new tablet SIM card took four days of arguing with T-Mobile representatives to activate. This time, I won't have an Internet connection with which to argue with them over, which'll make it even more painful.

I considered stopping by my mother's place on the way home to pick up my jury summons, but I remembered I couldn't get in. I didn't bring the key to my mother's place. In this situation, it was inconvenient no tot have the key on my main keyring, but in general, it's good for my sanity. Simply knowing that I can't go over there without warning (and thus, can't be *required* to go over there without warning for any reason) helps me keep thoughts of that place from seeping into daily life. Plus, I don't have to look at the key itself and be directly reminded.

Fred Meyer took back the bike lock and returned my money, no questions asked. I figured returning it'd be easy, but I expected them to at least ask *why* I didn't want it. To be fair though, it *was* still in the packaging. It's not like they thought I tried it and it didn't work out.

After reaching home, I decided to try checking in with other local carriers. As I said, I'm getting tired of T-Mobile's autopay games. I might switch to a more-expensive carrier just to be done with this idiotic fee nonsense; it's the principle of the matter, not the cost of the fees itself. First, I checked in with MetroPCS. Last I knew, they had a pay-in-person fee like T-Mobile proper, but unlike T-Mobile proper, MetroPCS was honest about it. I hoped they'd gotten rid of that stupid fee, but as expected, they hadn't. Next, I checked in with Devote30. Or rather, I *tried* to check in with Devote30. They've closed up shop and moved to Eugene though! So much for a shop I can pay my bill in person at. Lastly, I checked in with Cricket. They've never had a pay-your-bill fee at any time I used their services. However, they're now adding the same pay-your-bill fee MetroPCS has! What's up with these carriers and charging a fee to pay your bill!? In any case, that's the last of the carriers I know where to find locally. I can't escape this ridiculous fee without giving into their noxious demand that I not pay in cash in person.

I tried to fix my account through the Web interface, but the stupid thing is highly limited. T-Mobile tablet users are told the interface has been made easier to use, and forced to use this "easier" interface. Any attempts to use the main interface originally available to them and still available to smartphone users is met with this message and a link to the new interface. However, that interface is a pain and can't actually do everything you need it to. It won't let me turn my plan back on without switching plans, and it doesn't offer the option to switch to the one I'm on, as it thinks I'm still on it. I tried reaching out to T-Mobile support via their live chat option, but it's broken at the moment. It just silently fails to function. I tried disabling Privacy Badger, but that doesn't fix the issue, so it must be something even screwier on their end. I've reached out to them on Twitter, and hopefully we can get this fixed up tomorrow. Tomorrow will be my last day of service if today isn't.

I ran into my mother after work. They saw my bike; I wasn't ready to admit I had that yet. I also let slip a few other things I'd been planning not to. I mentioned the bus incident from the other day. They asked how my schooling was going, and I blabbed that I'll have a week off soon. I wasn't ready to commit to spending more time over there on my week off, but it's likely I'll be expected to now. I need to stay *away* from that place so I can recover! My mother brought me that jury summons they'd told me about. It seems the form they want me to fill out asks if I'm living in Coos County. If I'm not, it declares me ineligible for jury duty and demands I provide my current non-Coos address. All I have to do to get out of jury duty is tell them where I live. Perfect. Honestly, I'd like to serve on a jury some time for the experience. However, Coos County's too far away. I need a jury assignment within biking distance from home.

The cable company finally sent me an actual price via post. They've been sending me all sorts of advertisements, but none that actually tell what they're charging. Instead, the ads just tell me to come see them in Eugene or telephone them; neither of which is happening. The price in their new ad's actually 25% lower than the representative quoted me, but it requires a one-year service agreement. It's kind of ... too inexpensive not to look into now, at least in terms of dollars. I'll probably contact them again about it, asking what sort of info they need from me. Of course, if they demand a Social Security number or something, I'll have no choice but to refuse. I'll also ask if the price stays low after the year ends without another contract agreement. If a steady stream of contract terms are needed to keep the low price, it's not even worth looking further into. However, if I only have to get past the first year ... could it be worth it? I'll have to think on it further if it comes to it.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

include.d

I came across an interesting fact about what I believe to be the current standard date format: ISO 8601 defines a year zero. The problem with the Julian day numbers is that they put day zero off in a distant BCE period. Basically, day zero is in year negative four thousand something. The lack of a year zero between BCE and CE is a different issue, but I feel like by defining a year zero, we necessarily define a day zero, which such a year would begin with. Year zero is a much more sensible place to begin numbering days from.

I decided to leave the default date for my \st\y\datetime class as 1970-01-01 00:00:00, but I wanted to add two class constants to my \st\y\day_number class to allow easy use of a Julian day count or an ISO-8601-based day count. That didn't go as well as I wanted it to though. PHP's ... operator will unpack elements of an array only as the *final* arguments passed to a function, not the starting arguments. The current constructor of my class takes the date of day zero as the first three arguments, as they're the most likely to not be left on the default (and for now, a default doesn't exist), then takes other optional arguments after it. I either need to alter the constructor in an incompatible way or ignore the fact that passing further arguments to the constructor will require copying the array from the class constant, adding to it, then passing the new array into the constructor method using the ... operator. Obviously, the copy/alter array trick is messy; my users deserve better. That said, my users also deserve better than an ever-shifting API of incompatible changes.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Yst Dawson fades and Alex Yst takes further form

Day 00744: Monday, 2017 March 20

General news

It seems my T-Mobile plan's still set to expire on me, despite my having added funds to the account. The dumbed-down interface T-Mobile requires tablet account-users (as opposed to smartphone account-users) doesn't have the option of starting up the plan that it's already on, either. I'll have to wait 'til tomorrow (is the line actually expiring at midnight this time?) when the line'll be fully down to try then. Of course, if I can't get it working, I'll pester T-Mobile support again. I paid them $30.75 USD yesterday, so they're either going to make sure I can get my account going or they're giving my money back.

I tried to contact the cable company today to ask them more questions. Mostly, I want to know if the price will stay low after the first year without continued yearly service agreements and I *need* to know if I can set up an account without my Social Security number. Their live chat form seems to be busted today though. It was working the other day ... In any case, asking questions will have to wait.

I forgot to mention, but the other day, Discover sent me a postal letter telling me the information about my authorized user, Yst Dawson, is incomplete and they want me to complete it. I can't perform any update without providing a Social Security number though. I'm not looking to link a second identity to the account. I'm not looking for a joint account, I'm looking to authorize myself, under my preferred name, to spend my money! I can't update the name to reflect my own name change either. Anyway, I pulled up a live chat with a Discover representative today to try to get information about and resolve the issue. Long story short, Discover no longer has the option to add authorized users, as I already knew, and now only has the option to add partial-joint account holders with their identities tied to the account. Furthermore, if I don't downgrade Yst from being an authorized user to being a partial-joint account holder by adding their Social Security number (which is actually my own, but that name isn't tied to my Social Security number so they won't accept it), they're going to deactivate Yst's card on me. I'm taking this opportunity to cut ties with Discover. My Discover card's cost me a lot of money in domain name fees for domain names that I haven't actually been able to use, so it'll be nice to have that liability eliminated anyway. As Discover's proven they won't always block transactions when they say they will, closing the account's the only way to be sure to put the domain name charges behind me. I haven't closed the account just yet though. It could be useful for a couple more things strictly because it's getting canceled soon. For example, if I manage to get my T-Mobile account fixed, I might be required to set up autopay again. However, I can set up autopay on the dying card, so autopay can never actually get through, and there's no risk to me or my money. I'll simply pay in person every month and T-Mobile'll only *think* they'll be able to charge me automatically if I forget.

I spoke with a representative at Chase the other day to ask them about authorized users on their accounts. For chequing accounts, they require the authorized user come in in-person. It's not really possible for me to prove my real name yet though until I get it changed in court, which I'll likely do at some point. And once I *can* prove who I am, I'll no longer have any use for an "authorized user" card; I'll simply use a debit card from a credit union, most likely. As such, I can't get one of Chase's chequing accounts to fit my needs. Besides, if the authorized user has to prove their identity, they're not an authorized user at all; they're a partial- or full-joint account holder, which is exactly what I'm *not* looking for. However, there's a difference in how they handle chequing account "authorized users" and credit card account authorized users; that is to say, the credit card accounts are actually *able* to have authorized users added. I thought I'd have to wait to know if I was approved, but they actually let me know right away that I was approved, how much my line of credit's limit would be, and what interest rate they'd charge. Both the card issued to my real name and the card issued to my birth name will arrive in the mail in about a week. Though I'll be canceling my Yst Dawson credit card, my Alex Yst card will be in my wallet probably before the next time I buy something online!

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I seem to be losing my ambidexterity!

Day 00748: Friday, 2017 March 24

General news

I was irritable all day at work, and at first, I didn't understand why. I finally figured out it was probably either the stressful situation with the school threatening to drop me from my courses next term, my nightmare last night, or both. Once the stream of customers slowed down, I was able to listen to my music whle cleaning the back, and that did wonders for my mood.

I seem to be losing my ambidexterity. Originally, I was right-handed, but over the past three or so years, I've been using my left hand as much as feasible. I've gained proper strength and control in that hand, and for quite some time, have been able to use each hand about equally well, though certain tasks are easier for one hand while others are easier for the other. However, I cut a pizza with my right hand today, and found it didn't work so well. My right hand has atrophied a bit. I'm becoming left-handed! I still have the motor control, just not the strength to back it up. In the beginning, I used my left hand for most everything because that hand had so much catching up to do. After becoming ambidextrous, I should have started trading off and using both hands, but out of habit, I stuck with my left hand. I need to be more careful about that. Being left-handed is okay, I guess, but what's the point in having one crippled hand like most people when I can instead have two fully-functional hands?

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed it was raining at my apartment, and three bike-riding strangers were outside. They hinted that they wanted to come in, but I didn't feel safe about that because I didn't even know who they were. Were these people safe to have in my home? I pretended not to know what they were after, and was about to close the door, but they pushed their way in. I guess they'd be joining me for a bit after all.

As they came in, I became aware of a television in my apartment. Why was there a television though? Even in the dream, I knew I didn't have one here, I *wouldn't* have one here. A television does me no good, only harm. I must have known on some level that this was a dream though, as I *willed* the television out of existence.

It was late, so I headed to bed, leaving the strangers to entertain themselves. I woke up to find my mother cutting my hair without even talking to me about it first! My mother knew that the only way they'd be able to cut my hair to their desired style was to cut it when I was unable to turn them down. I was horrified as I looked in the bathroom mirror. My hair was a mess, only partly cut, and there wasn't anything I could do about it. Originally, I started growing my hair out because my mother threatened to boot me if I cut it to my desired style. Now though, I grow it out deliberately, as I want to try something new. It'd take months to regrow what they cut off, but my hair was now horribly uneven and had several groups of strands that were double the length of the rest of my hair. I couldn't cut those off, either, as that'd be even more hair to regrow and because it'd give my mother exactly what they wanted. Normally, I like to make people happy, but if you do something intentionally wrong, I want to make sure you're not rewarded for it. If you're rewarded for it, it gives you no incentive not to do it again. It teaches you that wronging others is a working strategy. How did my mother get into my home, anyway?

I went out to check on the strangers in the living room, saw them sitting and talking amongst themselves, then awoke from my dream.

University life

My program advisor replied to my letter to the billing department today. I'd been going to write directly to my program advisor today anyway to try to expedite the resolution the issue, as the billing department hasn't responded, time is short, my program advisor has said I can write to them about anything, and my program advisor is already known to respond. I'd be patient and wait, but there's no time! In any case, my program advisor has somehow been brought into the loop, and they say they've contacted the relevant department ... which should be the billing department that I already wrote to. I'm not sure if their email system sent my email to my advisor after screening it based on the "from" address, or what, but I'm thankful for their help.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Life was good today.

Day 00749: Saturday, 2017 March 25

General news

Every night at close at my workplace, we throw out a lot of excess food we've prepped. The problem is we keep too much ready, and we can't sell it all by the end of the night. On the rare occasion that we actually run out of food near the end of the night, we don't just make a little more to get us through 'til close, we make a bunch more. This is as our head manager instructs us; we're not the decision-makers, and on four out of seven days, the head manager is one of the closers, and is there to ensure it happens. The head manager might even be instructing us to do this because the store owner instructed *them* to make sure we did that, though I'm not sure. In any case, I always feel bad about the waste, and one of my shift leaders in particular feels bad about the wasted chicken wings. They say a chicken died for nothing, not even getting eaten. Last night, I took nine orders of wings home with me. I don't eat meat, but I do live in an apartment complex. My plan was to in the morning, see if one of my neighbors wanted them. That was a mistake I won't be making again. First, my shift leader bagged them haphazardly. The containers were every which way instead of all right-side up. I thought nothing of it at the time. When I got them home, I stuck the whole bag in my refrigerator like that. By morning, the wings had dripped goo in my fridge, which I then had to clean up. The wings weren't gooey last night, but they're now covered in a gelatinous substance. I thought that condensation in the containers mixed with ... something ... in the flesh of the birds. I wasn't sure what this stuff was exactly, but it wasn't presentable, so I had to throw it all out anyway. So much for saving some food. I kind of wondered if the goo was the makings of gelatin, but the shift leader reminded me today at work that it was probably just chicken grease. I'd forgotten how greasy chicken is. Even before I went vegan, I didn't really eat chicken, so I don't have any recent experience with the stuff.

The Chase representative told me two envelopes would come in the mail, one for each credit card. They both arrived in the same envelope though. The instructions that arrived with the cards said to activate them on the Web. They didn't even mention a way to activate by telephone, which is what most card instructions I've dealt with seem to require; I'm happy already! I did hit a bit of a snag, as I tried to activate the card under my real name before the one under my birth name. The website asked for a Social Security number ... and that would've been a problem. It turns out though that the website only allows activation by the account holder, not the card holder. Going through the activation process activated both cards at once. My one complaint is that they put my birth name's middle initial on the one card. I find use of middle initials to be a bit ... disrespectful. I mean, if you want to use a middle name, use it in full. If you can't even be bothered to put the full middle name, leave it out entirely. That won't be a problem once I get my name legally changed though. I'll no longer even have a middle name.

The cards come with this deal that if I charge $500 USD to them in the first three months, the bank'll give me back $150 USD of that. At first, I planned to simply ignore that deal. I don't plan to go on a wild spending spree. However, I've changed my mind. I'll charge things I normally would pay for in cash on the card, but still be buying what I'd already have been buying. I'm additionally going to buy some things I actually want, but've been holding off on. I'll try to hit the $500 USD target, but I won't go out of my way to do so. If I don't spend that much, I don't spend that much. One of the first things I'll pay for on with the card is a domain name renewal; I'd certainly be buying that eventually. Unfortunately, the local inexpensive grocery store, Winco, doesn't take credit cards. I won't be charging much food to the card.

Speaking of cards, one of the customers I served at work today says I'm their favorite till worker here. They wrote "See IS" on their card, and I actually card them every time. Too few of my coworkers do that; I've been told I'm the only one by another customer. The catch with me though is that you actually have to write "See ID", "Check ID", or the like for me to card you. If you write "CID", as some morons do, you haven't provided me any instructions to follow. "Cid" is a human name; you've simply signed your card in all caps under a name you probably don't identify as. I'm starting to accept SMS speak in general conversation, but there's no excuse for it on something as formal as a credit card. Still, checking ID only with the cards with properly-written instructions to do so is clearly more than most people do. It's hard to complain about.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed there was another world on the flip side of this one, a world os spirits and magic. I was a young, royal child there, though my family and I lived in an unfancy house that looked like all the others. I got ahold of the ingredients to mix a very special and forbidden dirt, one that would grant magical powers to those that came in contact with it. Before the events of the dream, I'd mixed the ingredients into two separate buckets, forming two separate and inert dirts. I ran with my buckets out our back door at night, locking the back door behind me. Somehow, my parents struggled with the door once they realized what I was doing and tried to stop me. In a rush, I mixed the two dirts to form the magical dirt, and as soon as I noticed magical light comeing from my left hand, which I was using to mix the dirt, I smeared it all over my body as quickly as I could. I nearly forgot to smear it under my clothing, but I did manage to get every part of me before my parents opened the door. I asked for help from the person that taught me how to make the magic dirt, who was standing outside my house, and they teleported me away, though I'd had to hurry with the dirt because that couldn't come with me for some reason.

Once away, my teacher sought the spirit of another child, and I tagged along. This child, being in our world of spirits, had corporeal form here, and didn't actually know they were dead. However, their parents were abusive, and they needed to escape. My teacher freed them from the spirit world, taking them to the regular world in which they were dead, and again, I followed. This world looked mostly the same as the spirit world, which might explain why my royal parents didn't have a royal house; such a royal house wasn't present in the regular world, so it didn't seep through to the spirit world. Once in this world, it was explained that this other child had been dead for a while. The parents they knew in the spirit world weren't even real, and their real parents were alive. It was implied without words that the child's real parents might not actually be abusive, and the figments of the spirit world might not match the personalities of the real parents. There were two sets of footprints in the mud as the three of us walked: my teacher's and my own; neither of us were dead, we were just denizens of the spirit world.

Flash forward in time, I was a bit older, living in the regular world. The magic dirt had granted me immeasurable power, but I needed magical energy to use any of it. I'd have been a great sorcerer in the spirit world, filled with magic, but I'd've been persecuted there too. In the non-magical regular world, there was barely any magical energy in the air, and I struggled to control my powers by making efficient use of energy. So far, I could only manage a sort of teleportation in which my body turned to light and I left an after image, and very limited flight. However, I was living a mostly-normal life, and was very happy.

University life

I should've taken my final exam yesterday, but I just wasn't feeling it. If my payment isn't accepted in time, will it even matter if I took the exam? Will the course just be considered dropped? Once the issue is resolved, but not in time for next term, will my grade be reinstated? I did take the exam today though; it's due tomorrow.

A bit after taking the exam, I received a letter form the school. The issue's been corrected! I no longer have to worry. Or at least, I no longer have to worry *for now*. Life is good again.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Little by little, I will reclaim my sanity, inner peace, and balance.

Day 00750: Sunday, 2017 March 26

General news

I tried to renew my domain name today, but Visa decided to screw with me with their Verified by Visa system. I've used Verified by Visa before with my credit union credit card, so maybe the problem isn't actually coming from Visa's end; it could be coming from Chase's end. I tried to get help from a Chase representative, but the bank's website wouldn't provide help unless I logged in, but also refused to *let* me log in. I figured I'd need to talk to a representative in-branch later, which turned out to be half true.

Next, I bought some custom lanyards. I've been saving up for them for a while. This transaction went smoothly, as the lanyard merchant doesn't use Verified by Visa. Later in the day, they emailed me with an even better offer. They catch is that they didn't know where to reach me until after my initial transaction with them and the new deal doesn't cancel the initial order. To take advantage of their better deal, I have to place a second order. The minimum order on the first transaction will leave me with more lanyards than I know what to do with though. I don't need a second order of them too.

The results of a Web search indicated I'd need to contact my specific bank to sign up for Verify by Visa. Perhaps registering for that would allow me to get past the error and prevent the bank from declining the transaction. I looked up how to register for Verified by Visa through my bank, and was lead to a page on the bank's website with a non-hyperlink Web address that supposedly allowed registration. However, I only reached a page saying "General error occurred." I tried again to log into by bank account online, as several hours had past since my initial attempt, and this time, it worked. I spoke asynchronously with a bank representative, who demanded I telephone a specific number to have the issue resolved. I explained that I have no telephone service. Now that SafeLink's dropped me, it isn't even the usual lie to get businesses to allow other contact methods as they should, but the actual truth. I explained I could reach them via the Web, email, or in branch, but not via telephone, and they replied that I should visit them in-branch. That surprised me quite a bit! Usually, when companies are adamant that I reach them via telephone, they don't seem to take "no" for an answer until I push back for several days or call their bluff by taking a somewhat drastic but reasonable action. In particular, financial institutions seem to have an incredibly strong tie to the telephone system, which is worrying. While we want our financial institutions to use the highest forms of security available, they require some transactions occur over the telephone system, an inherently insecure channel.

As an example of a drastic, reasonable action that get financial institutions to behave reasonably, I had to to ask a branch representative at Oregon Community Credit Union to close my credit card account with the credit union. They sent me a card in the mail with instructions on how to activate it via telephone. They didn't provide a way to activate online. So what did I do? I walked the card into my local branch and asked them to activate it for me. They refused. They told me I'd need to get ahold of a telephone somehow, perhaps borrowing one, and activate it via telephone. I again explained I didn't have access to any telephones, but they stubbornly refused to acknowledge the fact that not having telephone service is a completely valid choice to make. Having done all I otherwise could, i explained that a card I couldn't activate was of zero value to me, which was something even they could comprehend. Then I asked them to close the credit card account. That got them to change their tune! They'd rather help me in-branch than lose a card holder! And help me activate the card in-branch the did.

Today was laundry day, so I washed my work uniforms and other clothing. I thought I should've used the time spent waiting for the laundry cycles to complete to write up the beginnings of my journal entry for the day, but instead, I worked on sorting and organizing my home. The entryway was full of my belongings, still packed. That's also the only reasonable place to store my bike. I planned to keep it against the entryway wall, and I did at first, but it was too much of a pain to get it arround everything each day. I started stashing it in the middle of the entryway, then working around it all the time. I've cleaned up the entryway now though, as well as rearranged my bedroom a bit to accommodate most of the stuff from the entryway. Much of it was clothing bins and my underwear drawers, both of which I'd rather have in the bedroom anyway. I also donated several things, including some old candle jars and two pairs of leather shoes. I inherited those shoes from Cyrus, I'm almost certain. I'm sure they weren't mine, but Cyrus claims they're not theirs either, so when Cyrus escaped, they ended up with me. I can't wear them though, obviously, because we vegans don't wear corpse skin on our feet.

With laundry done and the entryway clean, I rode over to Chase to get them to fix the Verified by Visa issue, or at least *try* to get them to. I lost track of time though. It's Sunday. They're not open today! It's such a pain that everyone wants the same days off. We could have every business and service conveniently open every day if people would just stager their days off.

Chase is in Fred Meyer, Fred Meyer sells groceries and takes credit cards, and I was already there ... so I bought some food to make the trip worthwhile. THeir prices are higher than Winco's, but I'll never hit the $500 USD mark if I can't count groceries, especially if I can't renew my domain name either. My rent must be paid by cashier's cheque, not credit card, so I can't count that either. Seriously: one month's rent would more than hit the $500 USD target.

I'd packed one of those insulated bags given to me by my mother in my backpack, just to make surprise visits to the grocery store more fruitful. These things are *not* practical on a bike though. I need a bike basket or something to make grocery shopping more feasible. I'm used to living just a few blocks from the grocery store, but things have changed.

Today at work was interesting. First, one of my coworkers took on the moniker "Daddy Gummy Bear". I have no idea why, as the Crown of Voices keeps me from hearing most of what my coworkers discuss with one another, but it was quite amusing. Later, a strange group came through the drive-through, and one of them kept asking me to please spit on the pizza, sometimes with a bullhorn. Just before leaving, they asked "Will you show me your titties?". I don't think my shift leaders would approve if I decided to accept that request though. Later, a group came through, ordered a single pizza, then asked me to write "Quavo" on the box. There was only one pizza though, there wasn't any need to distinguish it from others. Or maybe they had other pizzas from my workplace at home? I don't know. A customer came in the front wearing a teeshirt printed to look like a Santa Clause suit bearing the text "Does this suit make me look fat?".

Another customer came through the drive-through and asked if I like working here. It got me thinking. Yes, I like working here. I didn't always like it, but my new, happier attitude is giving me rose-colored glasses in regards to several aspects of life. My neck and back aren't completely better, but they don't hurt so much any more, so work isn't so draining as it once was. My energy level has improved, compounding that effect. It's nice to get in some human interaction, both with my coworkers and with reasonable customers. Some customers are even fun and/or amusing! As for the customers that want to be a pain, I don't give them anything they can use against me. As soon as they drive off, they're out of my life 'til they come back. I enjoy being here now. I mean, sometimes I find myself heading into work not wanting to go quite yet, but it's not that I don't want to go in that day, just hat I want a little more time at home first. This work is by no means the best, but I do enjoy my work and I do enjoy being here.

The shift leaders conspired today to, near the end of the night, stop keeping chicken wings prepared and ready to order. As far as I know, neither is against the consumption of chicken, but they do feel bad about the six or so orders of chicken we have to throw out every night. I and at least one of my other coworkers appreciated that. If anyone wanted chicken, they could still buy it, they'd just need to wait the twenty minutes it takes to cook it. Of course, that wouldn't fly if the head manager were here, but they weren't. I wonder if we can do that again tomorrow and potentially the next day ... The head manager has Sundays and Mondays off. They work on Tuesdays, but they don't *close* on Tuesdays, so we might still be able to get away with not wasting chicken then too.

Toward the end of the night, I was washing dishes as quickly as I could in our three-basin sink, when one of the shift leaders shoved a pair of trays right in the middle sink where I was working. I moved them to the first sink, and they got weird about it. They wanted the trays in the middle sink *now*, even though the trays were in the way and even though the shift leader wasn't the one washing dishes. That annoyed more than it should have. Later, they put away a lid, but they didn't put it away correctly. Normally, I wouldn't have cared, but I was already annoyed with them, so I moved it to where the other like lids were right away. They gave me a funny look, so I explained that this is why I have to organize the lids every day. No one puts them away correctly, so they're always in a jumble until I get there. Ostensibly joking, they replied that maybe that's why I'm here. That really ticked me off! I'm constantly making up for everyone else's inadequacies and incompetencies here! The shift leader doesn't even care! No one keeps things organized but me. No one properly cleans anything, so I'm stuck pouring even more effort into trying to catch up with cleaning. Some of it's an impossible job alone, too. For example, we have these metal dough trays. They build up with oil and black grime. I can't scrape all the gunk off, as I'll get told off for taking too long with the dishes. Instead, I scrape a little bit off every time I do dishes. I should be making progress then, right? Wrong. There are so many dough trays, so little time, and I'm the only one actually scraping the gunk off. As such, the gunk builds up faster than I can clean it.

After a bit of thought though, I realized something: that's *not* why I'm here. I'm here to make money and to provide a reasonable contribution to the company for the wages I make. I'm not paid the same as five other workers; it's not my job to do the work of five people. I will continue to do my best in all areas I don't do so well at. I'll still continue to do better than my coworkers in the ways I excel. However, I'm done pouring everything into a job that doesn't appreciate me and doesn't benefit from my efforts. Does the store benefit from my trying to clean the pans properly when gunk build up faster than I can clean it? No. Does the store benefit from my daily organizing when the organization disappears as soon as I leave the store? No. As long as I'm the only one even trying, none of it will matter. Quite frankly, this place and these people don't deserve me. That said, I feel like I owe the head manager something. At this point, I'm a great worker that isn't going to disappear in the near future. However, they gave me employment even when I said I'd only be able to stay a month or two. That start is a huge part of how I was able to escape my abusive home situation. There's a strong possibility I'll try to stay until I get my associate's degree. That'll be about two years worth of good labor from me. Besides, as I said, I enjoy being here and I enjoy the work. I just need to be a bit less ... neurotic. Little by little, I will reclaim my sanity, inner peace, and balance.

I feel amazing. Today's been a wonderful day, despite a few bumps in the road.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Sorting old mail

Day 00752: Tuesday, 2017 March 28

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A broom
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts
My boss

Switch Kubbi subscription over to new credit card
Go pay other credit card bill (card was charged for Kubbi subscription)
Get old school to reissue reimbursement cheque
Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)

General news

The lanyard vendors seem to be a bit dense. I told them several times what text I want on the lanyards, but they just didn't seem to get it. I think the angle brackets in the text are somehow confusing them. In any case, I sent them a copy of the preview image their site gives me when I enter my desired text. That showed them clearly and exactly what I'm after, and their next "proof" came out perfectly.

My mother emailed me asking when to come by, but then didn't respond to my response for hours. I didn't know when they'd drop by, so I didn't want to start up a task I'd be unable to put down easily. I decided to start sorting my files, which have become particularly unruly since we left Coos Bay. Without a stable home, I didn't have my files set up as they should've been, and everything pretty much ended up in a deal-with-later pile. Having completed work on the newer file mess and still not having heard back from my mother, I moved on to my old files. They were full of old letters I'd never properly dealt with, among other things. I was always too tired and lifeless to actually open mail that I thought I knew what was. Sorting it, I found so much stuff I should've handled right away. I found tax forms I never used. I found insurance offers I never claimed. I found notices from my credit union about overdraft fees. In Coos Bay, I started putting my money in another financial institution, meanwhile, my Discover card continued to pull from my credit union account. My Discover card was pulling more than I realized, due to my old domain registrar continuing to pull funds from my Discover card without my knowledge. I found notice of several consecutive overdraft fees, and I could have, at a minimum, prevented all but the first if I'd been reading my mail. I found my old credit union credit card that I thought never arrived. To be fair though, when I requested my old card be marked compromised and a new card sent, the credit union never responded, so I wasn't on the lookout for the new card. To this day, my request is still marked on the credit card management website as an outstanding help request and hasn't been officially dealt with. I found a cheque from my old school from when they overcharged me. They refunded the difference, but I missed it at the time. I later found that cheque after it'd expired, but they wouldn't reissue it without a telephone call. I forgot to keep pestering them once I had more free time. I also found a piece of Cyrus' paperwork that somehow got mixed into my stuff. I'll need to find a way to get it back to them at some point. I didn't finish sorting *everything*, but I made huge progress and am mostly done. It could be some time before I get back to the rest, but I doubt I'll be adding more to the queue any time soon.

Eventually, my mother got back to me. They hadn't received my messages because their data connection had been turned off and they didn't realize they'd need it on to receive messages. Of course, if my mother hadn't been idiotic enough to sign up for continued service with a carrier that charges overage fees, they wouldn't need to turn their data connection off at all. A carrier that simply slows down the connection if you go over is so much more convenient, not to mention so much less expensive. This also explains why my mother thought I didn't respond to them yesterday when I did respond in a very timely manner.

My mother now wants to come over Thursday to do laundry instead of today. That's my only day off this work week, so they must've canceled the Portland trip after all. They did stop by to drop off the bags of food they don't want though. Most of it was saltines, pasta, and candy canes. I'd actually been wanting pasta for a while now, but I needed to finish a jar of jelly before I opened a can of marinara. That way, I can put the remainder in a nice jar instead of leaving it to chemically react with the tin can it came in. I forgot though; my plans on that had changed. One of the shift leaders said I should jack some marinara from work. We stopped selling bread sticks without marinara, so whenever someone wants bread sticks but no dipping sauce, they have to pay for the marinara anyway. Often times, they leave the sauce with us to sell to someone else. In other words, not only did a shift leader recommend I take it, this sauce has also already been paid for. Before work, I ate the last of my jelly on a sandwich, then took the small jar with me to fill with the red pasta/pizza sauce. After work though, after I got some of the spaghetti wet in a pan, I remembered I have no colander. I made it work, but I should get a colander at some point soon.

I'm actually considering the stupid contracted Internet service again. This time though, I'm approaching the topic with a bit more reason than last time. Specifically, if they raise my bill after the service term and contract expires, I leave. In part, this'll be an experiment. Today though, while sorting mail, I found an ad for a different company. Stupidly, they too require a service contract, but they're also offering less expensive service. I'll probably go with their service instead. That said, I don't want to rush into a decision. I'll wait until my mother leaves town to sign up for contracted Internet service. In part, this is an arbitrary wait period. In part though, this specific period is important. My mother's bipolar, or at the very least acts like it. They said they won't take me with them, but I think they'll change their tune. I need to stand up for myself and say I'm not going. If need be, I can cite my improved mental state here and that I still need time to fully recover from our toxic relationship. However, what I *can't* do is have something to fall back on, a crutch of sorts. I can't be locked into a contract, as I can then say "sorry, I'm locked into a contract for the year" and cite that as my reason for staying.

I've also been thinking about include.d's URI classes. Are they even really useful? At least most of them, probably not. I strongly considered discontinuing that branch in Git and ending that little subproject. However ... the actual production of them serves a purpose. The making of those classes leads me to learn the details of scheme-specific URI syntax, which I otherwise have no motivation to do. I'd like to finish up the /URI_research/ section of my website and put that chapter to rest. I'll probably pick up a more useful project after that, such as building a listing of vegan items available at non-vegan restaurants, useful when eating out with non-vegans that choose the restaurant. I've actually been meaning to do that for a while. I also need to continue on my story planning; I've thrown out some of my old element ideas and restructured my plan of completion. I'm now focusing on one element at a time in Floraverse order. The first element is Fire, so I'm mainly looking at mixed elements that involve Fire. I'm stuck on Fire * Plasma, which admittedly, is the first tertiary elemental combination. I'm sort of thinking about other combinations involving Fire at the same time, but that one combination is my main focus.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Spending the day with my mother

Day 00754: Thursday, 2017 March 30

General news

I type in a mix of Statesian English and English English (British English), and my spell checker doesn't like that. If I tell it to check in English without telling it whether I mean English English, Statesian English, or Canadian English, it figures I must mean Statesian English and highlights all the valid English English words not present in Statesian English. I'm done with this for now. I've switched my spell checker to use the real English, English English, and will try to consistently use English English spellings for the time being.

I've come up with the solution to my unbreaking pick recipe problem. I'm copying an old, defunct Minetest mod, Infinity Tools, a bit. They offer a new node for use specifically in crafting their unbreaking tools: the infinity block. After crafting lots of mese together to get compressed mese, two compressed mese need to be crafted together with an iron ingot to get an infinity block, one of three you'll need to craft a pick from. Instead of compressed mese, I have white mese, which is crafted in the same way. By today's standards though, it's nine times as much mese due to Vanessa Ezekowitz's modification to how mese works. Initially, they really screwed up the mese system, but eventually, they fixed it and everything worked out. They never really did understand how broken their new system was on a logical level, as far as I can tell, but they saw some unrelated issues caused when older maps were used with the newer game. Making the game compatible with older maps just happened to involve correcting the issue in the logic of the game as well. The break in logic had been a compatibility workaround to make older mods still function with the newer game, so when the even newer game was made compatible with older maps and older mods without that hack, it was removed. It's also worth noting that that didn't fix the entire issue with the new mese system, but I see the rest's been fixed while I was away from the game.

That got a bit off topic, but it's pre-event history, so I can't simply link to my previously-stated thoughts on the change, and leaving it out entirely makes for an incomplete story. Anyway, in addition to nine times as much mese being required for my version of compressed mese, my new nodes require twice as much compressed mese, in addition to more compressed diamond than compressed mese. I'm calling these new nodes "diamese", a very dense alloy of diamond and mese. These nodes *can* be placed in the world, but they can only be removed with a diamese pick. Anything else is just too weak. A diamese node requires 324 mese crystals and 405 diamonds to make, so a diamese pick requires 648 mese crystals and 810 diamonds to make. Surely, no one will complain that this pick is too easy to acquire. I'll need to actually draw up a texture for that node though.

My mother came to visit for the day, and we went on a short hike. That didn't last long though, as the rain started up. We went back to my place to do their laundry and talk a bit, and they asked me about the good knife they gave me. What knife? As it turns out, the food bags they brought over yesterday had a nice surprise in one of them, an old dollar store knife. These knives are honestly the best kitchen knives I've ever seen. I'm not sure how they ended up at a deep discount store, but we've not seen them in any store, save for rarely in second hand stores, for decades. I left some drink mixes in a couple of the bags, and in not emptying them completely, I'd missed the knife.

When I went to check out the knife, I found an email from my boss as well. They wanted me to pick up a shift today. Normally, I'd've jumped on the opportunity for more hours, but I couldn't really go with company over.

After the laundry was completed, we went out to eat at a mall, then went to a Goodwill second-hand store in Eugene. I found a mobile battery there for a dollar. It was the right brand, but could it possibly be the right *size*? I wish these batteries had the mobile model number printed on them. Thankfully, I had my mobile on me; I haven't always been carrying it lately. Due to the poor battery life, it's got to stay in airplane mode most of the time, so if I'm not using it as a music player or camera, what's the point? The battery fits almost perfectly. I'd say it's slightly lose, but that's only noticeable because I was looking for it. The device even powered on with the new battery! The new battery's kind of curved while the cracked battery is more rectangular on the edges, but it's close enough of a match to function. As I took it out to pay for it though, I noticed definitive proof that it's the wrong battery. My mobile and the cracked battery have four metal connectors each; the new battery has three. How does my mobile even turn on with this battery? In any case, I bought the battery anyway. Who knows, maybe this battery'll be better than the cracked one I've been using, even if it's not quite right.

Hanging out with my mother all day wasn't bad at all. I guess they're fine in smaller doses. They get to be a bit much when we're in the same house, but living apart, I can escape at the end of the day. In fact, I didn't even feel the *need* to escape. When we were living together, our outings were always on the edge of uncomfortable for me, but this time, everything felt fine.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I waled past someone in the driver seat of a motor vehicle, parked in a driveway, with the door open. They held a laptop playing a Floraverse video; a new update. I was too busy to stay and watch, but what I did catch was surprising. For starters, Floraverse had found the voice actors they were looking for! I'd thought it was a third-party fan work that needed voice actors, but it turned out to be Floraverse proper. Secondly, Doctor Neon had actually died, and Jupet had actually brought them back to life. Jupet wasn't sure if what they'd brought back was the original Neon though, and not a new entity created by reanimating the body. Doctor Neon seemed completely sure they were the original, but how would you actually know? If your memories are stored in your brain, and your body including your brain is brought back online, you'd have most of your memories and personality from before. There could be some loss either from decomposition, damage from that which killed you, or restructuring from that which brought you back, but you could be mostly the same with only unnoticeable differences.

It's also worth noting that Neon was brought back as a living stripegoat, not as an undead zombie stripegoat. I don't think Jupet has that power. It's also worth noting that it isn't Floraverse that made mention of a third-party use of their universe needing voice actors; it was Pepper&Carrot.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Improvements in Minetest, improvements in my understanding of Minetest, and losing my credit card

Day 00755: Friday, 2017 March 31

Unsponsored advertisements

Myuu has a new release, Tender Remains (Vocal Piano Version). It sounds like something I'd enjoy from the name, but I haven't had a chance to actually listen to it yet.

General news

I noticed when I picked up Minetest again that powered rails and carts had made it into the game. What I didn't realise right away was the implications. Last time I ran a server, my project was to build a long tunnel from the spawn area to a distant region. The plan was to move the spawn area to the other end of the tunnel upon completion, then dig an equally-long tunnel to somewhere else and start again. Because of the massive scale of the tunnel, by the time it was completed, many players would've left, and having a new spawn area would open up prime real estate again without destroying anyone's creations. It'd simply be another major town. At the time, I had a mod set up to allow everyone to create as many personal warp points as they liked too at no cost, so they wouldn't even have to walk far to reach their existing creations if they'd made proper use of the warp point feature. Instead of ever reaching my destination, I built several connections to the creations of others, and my tunnel became a transit line for pedestrians. Tunnel entrance requests poured in. I had a backlog of requests, so it was unlikely I'd reach my initial goal. Adding the carts mod was a frequent request. Players wanted quicker transportation through my tunnel; simply having a way to bypass the bumpiness of the surface terrain was nice, but they thought we could do better. This time, I planned to do something a little different, though I wasn't sure what yet. I'd build a huge tunnel for sure, just because that gives me a prime excuse to dig huge holes, yielding tones of minerals. However, I was going to keep my tunnel out of the centre of the map, where the spawn area is. This time, I would secretly be the administrator, instead of it being a well-known fact, so I'd have no special claim to the centre map block; someone else would surely take it before I had the materials needed to craft a protection node. However, it occurred to me what these new powered rails and especially the carts really mean for my Minetest world. I can set up the transportation tunnels everyone wanted! But I need the centre map chunk if I'm to do it right. There needs to be strict rules this time though. For starters, there needs to be a limited range in which I accept tunnel requests at first. Last time, someone requested a tunnel over half the length of my intended initial segment, but in a *perpendicular direction*. At that point, I lost all hope of getting where I wanted to go. I'm also going to need a decent level of planning. For example, one useful thing to add would be the option of connecting outside rails to my rails. At each surface hub, I should have my rails go all the way out my doors and to the edge of my land. That way, someone claiming the land next to mine would be able to, if they choose, continue the railway within the town.

While reading about the powered rails to make sure they were what I thought they were, I stumbled upon information about a new rare node, the PB&J Pup. It looked like some sort of companion to the Nyan Cat nodes, but it turns out it's actually a replacement. In the next version of Minetest, the Nyan Cat will finally be removed and the PB&J Pup will be filling its role! I enjoyed finding the Nyan Cats simply because they're rare, but otherwise, I was never really thrilled with them. For one thing, they're surrounded by copyright issues. At one point, the graphics of the node in-game were replaced to prevent legal issues, with a new image that supposedly didn't suffer from the problem of being too similar to the original, which was nonfree. However, I never really saw how that fixed the problem. The fact is, it was still fan art of a proprietary image. Now though, it seems the developers are getting it. They've removed the Nyan Cat altogether. Minetest's use for the Nyan Cat wasn't too similar to the original art though, so a drop-in replacement completely fixes the problem. Secondly, the Nyan Cat is a meme. Memes are stupid. It's nice to see the game now free of them. I'll admit that the texture of the candy trail left behind the PB&J Pup could use some work, but I still like this thing so much better. The PB&J Pup is *ours*. I mean, I don't care if someone else copies it, and I don't care if *we* copy something, as long as we're free to use it as we please. The Nyan Cat is proprietary, and has one or a few owners. The PB&J Pup belongs to us all.

The other day, I was looking through Minetest's settings and found a new one. It allows the administrator to set the boundaries of the world. There are three catches though. First, the limit is a single integer, not three or six. You can't set the dimensions of the world separately. Instead, the world is always cubic. Second, limits set above 31000 will be treated as 31000, which is the default. You can't grow the world, only shrink it. Third, map blocks are generated only within whole map chunks that reside within the boundaries. That last one is important. The settings file says map chunks are 5^3 sets of map blocks and makes some assumptions based on this fact. However, that "fact" isn't actually constant. It's settable in the configuration file before starting a new world and is world-specific. It only *defaults* to five. It only occurred to me today what that implies about the map boundaries though. The boundaries of the world stretch from node -30912 to node +30927. Neither of those is within sixteen of ±31000. Could there be other map blocks outside the default range, blocked off only because the world boundary doesn't align with the chunk boundary? To find out, I set the chunk size to one. Last time I did that, it really messed up world generation, but for experimentation, it works well. This time, the world generated mostly normally, though dungeon generation was admittedly badly warped. Dungeons were everywhere, and they all came out tiny and mangled. That didn't matter though. I teleported to what was formerly the edge of the map and the world stretched on. Not by much, but about as much as expected. The real limits of the game are -30976 and +30991. I found eight new map blocks in each of the three dimensions! I wrote up a short script telling the computer to find the chunk sizes that'd allow me to generate the full world, and it came up with 1, 3, 1291, and 3873. A chunk size of one is stupid and, if I understand correctly, inefficient. A chunk size of 3873 would generate the entire world in one go. That might be too intensive for my computer, and *would* be too much to store on my hard drive. A chunk size of 1291 would generate one twenty-seventh of the world at a time, and even that would likely put my computer under. I tried it in the name of science though, and thankfully, Minetest refused to start the server. It tried, but put this error message in the log:

ERROR[Main]: Some exception: "One or more noise parameters were invalid or require too much memory"

The game noticed there weren't enough resources and aborted. I also tried that last value, three. The dungeons are a bit mangled. In some spots, there are way too many dungeons. In other spots, there's none. I think it works well enough. The dungeons are basically just ruins. As long as they're not *too* mangled, they should be fine. Having them clustered also gives the illusion of ancient cities as opposed to people living evenly-spaced throughout the world. Vanessa E said that mods and even the engine often make assumptions based on the default chunk size. When the engine does that, it's a bit hacky. When *mods* do that, it's even hackier, and those mods shouldn't be used until fixed. The original developer agreed that the engine assumes the chunk size and that the dungeon misgeneration was a symptom of this. If the engine isn't built to work with different chunk sizes, why is the chunk size even configurable though? They said the only thing the developers try to guarantee when the chunk size isn't five is that the game won't crash. That should be good enough though. If the developers ever fix dungeon gen, my world won't have issues. If they *don't*, my world'll have a dungeon style not likely seen on other servers, making it stand out a bit. Either way, I win. Messing with the chunk size did have the completely foreseeable effect of erasing my PB&J Pup though. I hope to find a new one eventually, but hopefully this time only after my world becomes public. I sort of accidentally got a head start during testing this time.

The on-site manager's parent told me the other day that the bottle deposit in the state'd be doubling soon. My mother confirmed yesterday that it'd be tomorrow. I looked into it today to see if older bottles that still had the old deposit listed on the label would be accepted at the new price, and indeed they will. This document also explains several other things about bottle deposits in Oregon as well. For example, it's completely legal for that convenience store to limit bottle returns to fifty per person per day, while grocery stores tend to be required to take at least up to one hundred forty-four. The amount they're required to take seems to depend on the size of their building or property. It's also legal for the restaurant I work at not to accept bottle returns at all. As long as we don't charge a deposit, we don't have to take the bottles back. That makes me wonder though. If businesses aren't required to charge a deposit, why *do* they? They could build that cost into the cost of the drinks themselves. Before I knew that'd get them out of taking back the bottles, I'd already wished they'd be upfront about the cost by including the soda and the deposit in a single price. Now though, I see the advantage of keeping it separate just to provide places required to take them back. Lots of people won't recycle without the monetary incentive.

I discovered a new feature of the cash registers at work that allows me to enter in an amount of something bought and have the item listed as (for example) five of that item, instead of one of that item five times. That should save a little till paper! It's not much, but it'll add up. The problem is we don't get trained to use these machines properly. We're just shown the basics and told to have at it.

This new mobile battery doesn't last long, and even worse, I don't have access to my mobile's internal file system any more and my music on the external SD card keeps appearing to vanish. Using the cracked battery that's at least the right type fixes the problem. Clearly, it was a bad idea to use the wrong size of battery. I'm going to have to get an actual replacement at some point.

I seem to have lost my credit card, and now I'm kind of panicking. Normally, I leave my card at home and use it only for online purchases. When it goes missing, I know I misplaced it around my home. But now, this new credit card account is supposed to give me cash back if I spend enough on it, so I've been using it around town if I buy things too. I had it yesterday, and I pulled it out to buy lunch. However, it's not in my wallet now. I must not've put it away. Now, I can't find it. I either pulled it out of my pocket and put it somewhere when I got home or I dropped it somewhere. I'm not sure what to do aside from record the date it went missing (by way of this paragraph in my journal) and keep an eye out for purchase notifications for things I didn't buy. If it doesn't show up after a period of time or if I see unauthorised transactions, I'll report the card as lost or stolen, respectively.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.